[Music]
so guys this is a very quick film about
rebel wisdom live
we had an amazing event last night
within McGilchrist the author of
mastering his emissary and we also
recorded an interview with him in this
room that we're going to release as well
in the next couple of weeks we're gonna
put a few clips from the live event in
this film starting now you know this is
called rebel wisdom I just want people
to be rebellious against the status quo
all the things you're told all the
managerial guff that overlays the
reality and vividness and vitality of
our lives and come down to the brass
tacks of what's important and stand up
for it so thank you to everyone who
tuned in to livestream last night and
also thank you to everyone who came to
the event we sold out which was great
the level of conversation in the
livestream was brilliant was actually
really funny lots of fun and the quality
of the questions was also excellent and
we actually asked Ian some of the
questions from the live stream like this
one so we'll take a question from the
live stream which is from Jenny Magnus a
consistent thread through the book is
the idea betweenness could even say more
about what he means by this and why it's
important yes try to do this briefly and
think of an electric current it's it's
manifest between two poles a positive
and a negative pole it's not in the
positive pole it's not in the negative
pole it's not even in the positive pole
plus the negative pole nor is it in the
space between the two poles because that
space is nothing it's in the hole
between this of the two poles and what
that brings about at a wholly different
level a good analogy is music music is
all between this so take a note an
a-flat
what does it mean absolutely nothing
take another one Abby
it means absolutely nothing put 30,000
of these things together and you've got
varsity minor mass so what happened
there which means a hell of a lot and
it's not in the notes so it must be in
the spaces between the notes but the
spaces between the notes and a melody
are just silence the spaces between
notes in harmony are just silence the
spaces between the beat of the rhythm
are not bad
what say you put a lot of things that
mean nothing together and a lot of
spaces that mean nothing together you
find something that means more than
almost anything you can experience in
the world how does that happen the
answer is if you like between this so
what we underestimate bringing it down
to earth is that we are not you know we
are not atomistic there is no way in
which I exist independently of all of
you and of all of the the planet and all
of the people who came before me and
indeed in a strange way I'm part of
something that is to come that is all
not in me or in them or in some sort of
gaps between us but is in the between us
that's what I mean by it and it's thank
you Jenny for raising the point because
it is absolutely fundamental to my
philosophy and it's another way of
talking about what I was talking about
earlier that I'm writing about right now
so we've been talking a lot about how we
do this going forward and what we've
decided is that we're going to obviously
always stream the talks live on YouTube
so anyone who wants you can tune in and
then we're going to put the film of the
talk up on patreon and anyone who's a $5
plus a month subscriber can watch the
talk in its entirety when it's up there
so we've actually stolen this format
from Sam Harris from any of the same
reasons a major one is that a live event
is it's quite a different beast to sit
down interview and we don't have as much
control over the quality of it so the
event video that we're showing clips
with here is not the same as the live
feed it's the it's the feed from the
camera that's running at the same time
so it's high-res
it's better quality than the live stream
but as it's a similar decision as you
said that Sam Harris made which is the
the best quality content the the
podcasts or the interviews that we're
doing where we can definitely sort of
control the environment that is a sort
of signature dish so we're going to put
that out on the main channel and the
events which are slightly harder to
control will be for patrons only
and generally whenever we're doing a
live event we're going to have an
interview with that guests at the foot
beforehand we'll get them in to the
studio a little bit before the event so
we'll have the interview to go up
alongside and we also have to think sort
of long term about how we make this
sustainable and the way to do that that
we've chosen is to really ramp up the
patreon content and increase the number
of people who are subscribing on patreon
so and also at the same time we're going
to be taking questions we're trying to
involve the community as much as
possible in this conversation asking
them for questions for our upcoming
interviews asking the livestream
audience for questions during the live
stream a little bit like this one there
play another clip it's mine no matter
aspects are the same thing what is that
thing well of course we did have a word
for it but then can I answer with an
analogy everybody knows what water is
it's a transparent liquid that flows but
there's also this funny opaque very cold
substance that is entirely a mobile
ice there is also this absolutely
invisible something in the air which is
also water vapor so water exists in
different phases which of them is water
they're all water if you like or they're
all not water there
now I see the relationship very briefly
I'd need a lot longer between matter and
consciousness as being like this that
consciousness is as it were the final
substrate matter is something a form of
consciousness and element in
consciousness in physics terms a phase
of consciousness in the same way that
ice is a phase of water so see the rest
of Emma Gilchrist divided reign divided
world stand up as a patron and the next
rebel wisdom live is going to be a
little bit different than the ones we've
had before
it's called occult politics in the time
of chaos and we've got two speakers
there's Gary Lachman who's been on the
channel before and he's written a book
called Dark Star rising
looking at how the occult and esoteric
practices influence Trump's rise to
power and how they might still be
influencing world politics and then we
have Julian vane who is also an expert
on esoteric culture and history and
written a number of books so we're gonna
have both of them we're gonna have both
of them up for the Q&A and it's going to
be very very interesting I think so tune
in for that that's going to be on
December 4th in London live but
obviously live streamed as well and
there'll be more information than that
before it happens
thank you for watching and see you soon
[Music]
you